

# **AMAR NATH**

+91 - 9654542742

amar.ncet@gmail.com

Bangalore, KA, India

in <u>linkedin.com/in/connectamar</u>

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

PRODUCT SECURITY

IAM

**SECURITY ENGG** 

**NETWORK SECURITY** 

**AUDITING** 

**OT SECURITY** 

**CLOUD SECURITY** 

BCP

**SECURITY OPERATIONS** 

PROJECT MGMT

GRC

**DEVSECOPS** 

loT

FORENSICS

### PERSONAL SKILLS

\_\_\_\_

**LEADERSHIP** 

PROBLEM SOLVING

CRITICAL THINKING

INTERPERSONAL

**CREATIVE THINKING** 

NEGOTIATION

**DECISION MAKING** 

# DOMAINS

- ✓ PRODUCT DEVELOPMENT
- ✓ AEROSPACE & DEFENCE
- ✓ TELECOM
- ✓ BANKING & INSURANCE
- ✓ MANUFACTURING
- ✓ EDUCATION
- ✓ PHARMACEUTICAL
- ✓ SEMICONDUCTOR

#### CONTRIBUTIONS

- ✓ OWASP MEMBER
- ✓ INFOSEC INSTITUTE CONTRIBUTER
- ✓ CCCURE AUTHOR

Result oriented and an avid learner with a passion for innovation in security arena. 13 years of experience with focus on strategizing and delivering security programs at enterprise level covering IT, OT and cloud with keen problem solving and analytical skills.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### NOVARTIS: DIRECTOR - SECURITY SOLUTIONS ARCHITECT [Feb, 2020 - Present]

- ✓ Define, deliver and maintain future-fit information security architecture principles, standards and technology roadmaps to support the secure design and implementation that address full stack security requirements.
- ✓ Identify and develop Global Security Architectural Standards, Design Patterns, Reference Architectures and Roadmaps used to define the security principles and constructs in which all products are designed to incorporate consistent and appropriate security controls.
- Monitor projects with high strategic impact to ensure processes are being followed and goals achieved, including completing milestones on time and within budget.
- ✓ Engage with architects, technical leads and R&D Engineering & Development teams to ensure the security considerations are inducted well in advance during the product development cycle.
- ✓ Work with solution architects to provide mitigation and potential remediation recommendations for solving unprecedented issues and problems.
- Maintain deep understanding of the information security landscape and emerging technologies and identify key implications and actions for security architecture to maintain a forward-thinking approach.
- ✓ Evaluate and select the technologies and tools required for the delivery of the cyber security target architecture for software, infrastructure in partnership with Enterprise Architecture.
- ✓ Deliver KPIs/metrics for security architecture for management reporting stakeholders. Produce necessary metrics to demonstrate overall completeness of defensive strategy.
- ✓ Collaboratively define and prioritize security backlog for products that continuously delivers measurable value towards the vision.
- Communicate with a broad range of senior stakeholders to exhibit business alignment.
- ✓ Coach and mentor architects with functional reporting.
- ✓ Contribute to organizational whitepapers and represent in industry consortium for practice standardization.

#### PREVIOUS EXPERIENCE

- APPLIED MATERIALS [ OCT,2019 FEB, 2020] SECURITY ARCHITECT
- BNP PARIBAS [ APR,2016 OCT,2019] MANAGER SECURITY & IT RISK

METLIFE [ APRIL 2012 - MAY 2014] - TEAM LEAD - CYBER SECURITY

- ICS PVT LTD [FEB,2016- MAR, 2017] SECURITY CONSULTANT
- IDEMIA [ MAY,2014 FEB,2016] SENIOR SECURITY ANALYST
- NESS [ JULY,2010 APRIL 2012] MEMBER OF TECHNICAL STAFF
- IIT, KGP [SEP,2009-FEB,2010] RESEARCH ASSISTANT

## **CERTIFICATIONS - TECHNICAL**

- CERTIFIED CLOUD SECURITY PROFESSIONAL (CCSP)
- CERTIFIED INFORMATION SYSTEMS SECURITY PROFESSIONAL (CISSP)
- INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY INFRASTRUCTURE LIBRARY (ITIL)
- MICROSOFT CERTIFIED: SECURITY, COMPLIANCE, AND IDENTITY FUNDAMENTALS
- MICROSOFT CERTIFIED: AZURE FUNDAMENTALS

## **CERTIFICATIONS - MANAGEMENT**

- BUSINESS FOUNDATION WHARTON, THE UNIVERSITY OF PENNSYLVANIA
- STRATEGIC LEADERSHIP & MANAGEMENT UNIVERSITY OF ILLINOIS URBANA-CHAMPAIGN
- BUSINESS MODEL INNOVATION HEC, PARIS
- STRATEGIC MANAGEMENT IIM, BANGALORE
- INNOVATION AND INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY MGMT IIM, BANGALORE

## **EDUCATION**

- PG-DIPLOMA INFORMATION SYSTEM & CYBER SECURITY, CDAC, PUNE 2010
- B.E COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING, N.C.E.T, BANGALORE 2009